http://kids.columbuslibrary.org/privacy-statement

Skip to main content (Press Enter).
Start of main content
Welcome to the Columbus Metropolitan Library (CML) website. We hope you find this website to be valuable and enjoyable. CML operates several websites and utilizes a collection of online services, including, without limitation, various communication tools, social networking features, third party services, and other features, content, and applications accessed via the Internet, mobile, or other device. This collectively is the Website.
Some library services require a CML library card or registered user website account. Registration for CML library card and website account requires personal information. We use this information to improve services to you. This Privacy Statement applies to all registered and non-registered users of the Website and online services. This Privacy Statement applies to user personal information in the registration, preferences, Website settings, and correspondence information when you contact us for customer service purposes. This Privacy Statement also applies to non-personally identifying information (site usage, interests, demographics) associated with users accounts and access. When users access the Website, we may collect non-personally identifiable information about those visits and our servers receive and record information about your computer and browser, including potentially your IP address, browser type, and other software and hardware information. We also use cookies and may use other tracking technologies. Third parties that support CML may also use these technologies to collect similar information. CML does not govern these third party technologies nor is responsible for the privacy practices of such third parties. You should check the applicable privacy policy of the third party website and/or service and use is governed by the privacy policies of the third parties. Please protect your computer and your concerns by staying safe online and being aware of online security, phishing, malware, password safety and family safety and other practices for safety online. If your personal or account information needs to be modified you should use the controls on the Website to update information, and if you forget your password you should use the controls on the Website to receive access to your settings, whereby you should set a new password.
CML uses and shares information to deliver services to you and CML shares information with third party application and service providers. CML stores data in the United States, and potentially outside the United States, when using third party services and hosted solution providers. We will not share personal information about library customers, except to parents/guardians of minors, or unless required to do so by a court order or legal requirement. We may send email to you to provide information about library services and offerings, and/or to seek your feedback in order to provide new and improve services. By providing your email address CML will include your email address in the distribution of such library notices. If you want to discontinue or modify your receipt of emails from the library, use the unsubscribe functions located in the email and/or website functions to discontinue email.
You may cancel your registration and delete your account through commands located on the Website. If you cancel your registration remember that even after you cancel your account, copies of some information of your account may remain viewable in some third party applications or websites, and that CML may also retain backup information related to your account on our servers for some time after cancellation. Because of caching technology, your account may not be accessible, or there may be a delay in the removal of the content from elsewhere on the Internet.
CML may modify this Privacy Statement as necessary. The most current version of the Privacy Statement will supersede all previous versions. We will provide at least thirty (30) days notice before any material changes take effect. If you disagree with such changes simply discontinue your use of the Website and/or applicable services before the changes take effect. Your use of the Website and/or continued use of our service after changes are made signifies your agreement to such changes.
If you have questions about the Privacy Statement, please Contact Us.
Privacy Statement Version 1.0—effective 02/14/2012
